

CONTACT INFO

muhammadazhariqbal@icloud.com +92 3422740802

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Organization Skills
- Communication
- Time Management
- Proactive, initiative, creative and engaged

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML | CSS | BOOTSTRAP
- JavaScript ES6
- REACT JS | REACTSTRAP | MUI
- React Native Expo | CLI
- Firebase
- Version Control

CERTIFICATIONS

Introduction to Web Development. (Jan 8 , 2020) an online non-credit course authorized by University of California, Davis and offered through Coursera

M AZHAR IQBAL FRONT-END DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an enthusiastic front-end developer with 1+ years of working experience in bringing creative UI design concepts and ideas into realistic applications using Front-end Technologies HTML/CSS, vanilla JS, React JS, React Native, and different frameworks/libraries.

I enjoy being challenged and engaging with projects that require me to work outside my comfort and knowledge set, as continuing to learn new languages and development techniques are important to me.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Designer

Fiverr

JUN 2020 - OCT 2020 (5 MONTHS)

- Designed Static websites and Landing pages for clients.
- Mostly Worked on HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.

Freelance Front-end Developer

Fiverr

OCT 2021 - DEC 2021 · (3 MONTHS)

- Designed and Developed Web & Mobile Applications.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobilefirst approach and strategy.
- Worked on HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React JS, React Native, and Firebase.

Front-end React JS & React Native Developer

DevelopEirs. Dublin, Ireland JAN 2022 - JUN 2022 · (6 MONTHS)

- Implemented websites and mobile applications from concept through development.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobilefirst approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Worked with agile methodology, React JS, React Native, Firebase, Material-UI, Agile Project Management, and Google Analytics

Certified Web Designer. (Nov, 2019 - Jan , 2020) Usman Institute of Technology, Karachi.

Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4.
(Jan 11, 2021)
An online non-credit course authorized by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology and offered through Coursera

Front-End Web Development with
React JS.
(March , 2021)
An online non-credit course
authorized by The Hong Kong
University of Science and Technology

Web and Mobile App Development. (April, 2021) Expertizo University

and offered through Coursera

Freelance React JS / React Native Developer

Fiverr

JUL 2022 - SEP 2022 · (3 MONTHS)

- Worked on React JS/ React Native-based Projects.
- Designed & Developed E-commerce Web apps.
- Developed Portfolio Websites, MVP Products related to Tenants Management, and Warehouse Product Management.

Freelance React JS / Next JS Developer

Upwork. Contract

SEP 2022 - OCT 2022

 Worked on React JS / Next JS and Material UI-based Projects.

Freelance React JS Developer

Fiverr. Contract

OCT 2022 - PRESENT

 Working on a web application for boarding schools for managing students, their groups, team captains, teachers, events, games, awards, etc with some analytics capabilities.

EDUCATION

MATRICULATION - COMPUTER SCIENCE Merit n Merit school | 2017

INTERMEDIATE - PRE ENGINEERING Government Gulshan College | 2017-2019

BACHELOR IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
Bahria University Karachi Campus | 2019-Present